<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Slumdown</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Slumdown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>J Entering and Saving Data</title>
      <link>/post/j-entering-and-saving-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/j-entering-and-saving-data/</guid>
      <description>(Marin video on this topic: R tutorial 1.3)
If our data set is small it is quite simple to type the numbers in to the R console to do our analysis. With a larger data set, especially one we might want to come back to later, it is a good idea to enter the data into a spreadsheet program such as Excel and load it into R.
There are several ways to set up your spreadsheet file but the simplest is to save it as a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K Correlation</title>
      <link>/post/k-correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/k-correlation/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we will learn how to calculate a Pearson Product Moment Correlation Coefficient with R. We will also calculate Spearman’s Rho on the sample data set.
Let’s revisit the data set we used before for the information from the activity tracker my daughter gave me.
Date 11/25 11/26 11/27 11/28 11/29 11/30 12/1
Steps 16.8 7.1 8.3 10.8 14.3 11.2 13.0
Goal 12.0 12.3 12.0 10.7 10.7 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K1 corrplot</title>
      <link>/post/k1-corrplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/k1-corrplot/</guid>
      <description>“corrplot” is a useful package for doing exploratory analyses of correlational data. This turorial will demonstrate the basic fetures of the package using the “CorExample2” data set. This dataset contains pre and post test scores for 66 subjects on a series of reading comprehension tests. When I imported the data I shortened the name to CorEx just to save some typing. I have already installed the “corrplot” package and as well as importing and attaching the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L Regression With R</title>
      <link>/post/l-regression-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/l-regression-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Marin video reference 5.1
Import and attach the LungCapData set
We will be working with the variables Age and LungCap
It is a good idea to begin with a scatterplot of the data. We will make Age our X or predictor variable and LungCap our Y or predicted variable.
plot(Age, LungCap) We generally want to calculate the Pearson r for any data on which we will do a regression analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M Checking Regression Assumptions</title>
      <link>/post/m-checking-regression-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/m-checking-regression-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Reference: Marin Video 5.2
WHile we will not be doing much with this information, there are several easy tests we can perform to deteremine whether a linear regression is a proper approach for eplaining a relationship.
First, Import and attach the LungCapData set.
Next, run the code we used in the last Crib Sheet to generate the regression analysis.
plot(Age, LungCap) mod&amp;lt;-lm(LungCap ~Age) summary(mod)  ## ## Call: ## lm(formula = LungCap ~ Age) ## ## Residuals: ## Min 1Q Median 3Q Max ## -4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N Multiple Regression in R</title>
      <link>/post/n-multiple-regression-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/n-multiple-regression-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Multiple Linear Regression (R Tutorial 5.3)
Simply put, multiple regression is a technique which allows us to use more than one predictor variable with a single predicted variable. Multiple regression is beyond the scope of this course but it is fairly easy to perform in R. These notes might come in handy if you ever take a more advanced statistics course and want to do a multiple regression analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Binomial Distribution</title>
      <link>/post/o-binomial-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/o-binomial-distribution/</guid>
      <description>The Binomial Distribution is a distribution of probabilities where there is a known number of trials, a known number of desired outcomes (often referred to as “successes”), and a known and stable probability of success. We are most often interested in the probability of a certain outcome or the probability of any of several outcomes for these distributions.
The two R functions of most use to us in dealing with binomial distributions are “dbinom” and “pbinom” functions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P Normal Distribution</title>
      <link>/post/p-normal-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/p-normal-distribution/</guid>
      <description>Reference: Marin video 3.3
The function “pnorm” will return the probability associated with any X value in a normally distributed population of scores. For example the probability of obtaining a score of 70 or less - p(x&amp;lt;=70) - from a population with a mean mu=75 and standard deviation sigma=5 would require the following R code:
pnorm(q =70, mean = 75, sd = 5, lower.tail=T) ## [1] 0.1586553 The result (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q t tests with R</title>
      <link>/post/q-t-tests-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/q-t-tests-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Reference: Marin videos 3.4, 4.1, 4.2, and 4.4
Reading the output from a t test. The “t.test” command produces a table similar to the following. This example uses a two group t test and assumes that the groups have equal variance. We will discuss these issues further when we consider the Independent Groups t.
t.test(LungCap~Smoke, mu=0, alternative = &amp;quot;two.sided&amp;quot;, conf.int = 0.95, var.eq = T, paired = F) ## ## Two Sample t-test ## ## data: LungCap by Smoke ## t = -2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Chi Squared </title>
      <link>/post/r-chi-squared/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-chi-squared/</guid>
      <description>Reference: Marin (R Tutorial 4.7) Chi Squared is a very useful test for evaluating categorical data. Perhaps the greatest difficulty students have with it is determining which version should be used in a particular situation and how to enter the data into R. We will do several examples, showing various ways to evluate information.
Single Classification Chi Squared We use the single classification test when we have only a single variable of interest (even though there may be several levels of that variable).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S Mann-Whitney U </title>
      <link>/post/s-mann-whitney-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/s-mann-whitney-u/</guid>
      <description>## Warning: Missing column names filled in: &amp;#39;X3&amp;#39; [3], &amp;#39;X4&amp;#39; [4] The Mann-Whitney U test (also known as the Wilcoxon Rank Sum Test) is a useful alternative to the Independent Groups t when the assumptions of the t are not met. It is sensitive to tied ranks so is best used when the data set is relatively small or the measurements are sufficiently precise as to make duplicate scores unlikely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T Wilcoxon Matched Pairs Signed Ranks Test</title>
      <link>/post/t-wilcoxon-matched-pairs-signed-ranks-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/t-wilcoxon-matched-pairs-signed-ranks-test/</guid>
      <description>Reference:Marin R Tutorial 4.5
Data set: BloodPressure
Read the data set in to R and attach it. As always, it is a good idea to produce a graphic so we can better visualize our data. A box plot is appropriate in this case.
boxplot(Before, After) We may also want to see a summary of the data. I renamed it “BP” to save some typing.
summary(BP) ## Subject Before After ## Min.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U One Way ANOVA in R</title>
      <link>/post/u-one-way-anova-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/u-one-way-anova-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Reference: Marin video R Tutorial 4.6
Data set: DietWeightLoss
Download and attach the data set if you want to follow along.
Analysis of Variance or ANOVA is one of the most common and powerful statistical techniques available. While ANOVA designes can become quite complicated, the single factor design is quite straightforward and easy to understand. It is also very simple to perform in R.
The null hypothesis (Ho) for the ANOVA is that all groups will perform equally (in this case, lose of gain the same amount of weight).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U1 - Kruskal-Wallis Test</title>
      <link>/post/u1-kruskal-wallis-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/u1-kruskal-wallis-test/</guid>
      <description>If the assumptions of the ANOVA are not met, we might choose to perform a Kruskal-Wallis test.
kruskal.test(WeightLoss ~ Diet) ## ## Kruskal-Wallis rank sum test ## ## data: WeightLoss by Diet ## Kruskal-Wallis chi-squared = 15.902, df = 3, p-value = 0.001188 Note: Some versions of R seem to require that the group variable be an integer rather than a character for the kruskal.test command. I added a third column (NumDiet) to the spreadsheet which replaced the character variable “Diet” with an integer value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V Two-way ANOVA</title>
      <link>/post/v-two-way-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/v-two-way-anova/</guid>
      <description>This example is based on sample problem 16.1 in Robert Pagano’s Understanding Statistics in the Behavioral Sciences, 10th Edition.
The study looks at the effects of exercise on sleep.
There were two times of day, Morning and Evening, and three exercise conditions, Light, Moderate, and Heavy. This was a completely randomized design, where each subject appeared in only one condition. Thus, we have a 2X3 ANOVA design and can evaluate main effects of Time of Day and Exercise, as well as any interaction that might exist between these two factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W RM ANOVA</title>
      <link>/post/w-rm-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/w-rm-anova/</guid>
      <description>###Data Wrangling
Repeated measures spreadsheets are usually set up in “wide” format, with a row for each subject and a column for each observation. R requires that the data be in “long” format, with a column for Subject numbers, a second column for Trials, and a third column for Scores. We will be using a data set (Kwide) which is in the wide format.The “head” command will show us the first several rows of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Things and Stuff</title>
      <link>/post/statistical-things-and-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/statistical-things-and-stuff/</guid>
      <description> I am going to write things about statistics.
But first, a Header and then a picture:
and then a link: Placekitten
And then some itallics and then some BOLD
and then a list:
 this that the other  and finally, a numbeed list:
that this the other   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial part 1: Getting started</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>A sort summary of how to get started using the slumdown package. It discusses how to install the package, set up a new site, and where to look for initial configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial part 2: Writing a post</title>
      <link>/post/writing-a-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/writing-a-post/</guid>
      <description>Like any blogdown post, a slumdown post is written in R Markdown, and uses a few custom fields in the YAML field. This tutorial provides an illustration of how different kinds of content are displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial part 3: Colour palettes in slumdown</title>
      <link>/post/colour-palettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/colour-palettes/</guid>
      <description>The main reason I wrote slumdown (besides boredom) was to make it easy to  include user-defined colours palettes in blogdown, and expose those palettes to R so that (for instance) plots can be drawn in a style that matches the blog style. This tutorial introduces this palette system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial part 4: Customising the header</title>
      <link>/post/customising-headers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/customising-headers/</guid>
      <description>Slumdown allows the user to control the background image at the top of each post, the profile image overlaid in the middle of that image, and the caption attached to the header image. This post describes how this is done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial part 5: Deploying to GitHub</title>
      <link>/post/deploying-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deploying-to-github/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial describes how to deploy a site. Blogdown sites are very often deployed to Netlify, but I have a personal bias to use GitHub Pages, so &lt;em&gt;slumdown&lt;/em&gt; is configured by default to use GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial part 6: Some notes on Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/notes-on-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/notes-on-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Eventually, this will be an explanation of how the Hugo slum theme is designed, possibly accompanied by a brief tutorial on Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A kunoichi page</title>
      <link>/project/kunoichi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/kunoichi/</guid>
      <description>A simple project page illustrating how user-defined themes in &lt;em&gt;slumdown&lt;/em&gt; can be used as the basis of individual pages and ggplot2 figures. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t do very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description> Resources for PSY 301 This website contains resources for my undergraduate statistics students as well as material that might be of use to students Research Methods and Senior Seminar. Most of these resources are available in the learning management system for PSY 301 but, for students not currently enrolled in that class, this may be a more accessable resource.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>